<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Effin' Tasty</title>
    <description>Effin' Tasty is a cooking site dedicated to food, and the tastiest ways to prepare it. We have recipes and prep techniques, along with delicious pictures.
</description>
    <link>https://effintasty.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://effintasty.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 08:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 08:15:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Muffins</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat over to 350 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all dry ingredients in medium bowl and whisk thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all wet ingredients in large bowl and whisk thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gradually spoon dry ingredients into wet ingredients until fully incorporated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fully grease your mini-muffin pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill each muffin mold about 2/3 full.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 10-15 min, turning halfway through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confirm doneness by inserting a toothpick and seeing if it comes out clean.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool on a wire rack. Once fully cooled, remove muffins from their tin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/snacks/2024/08/28/snacks-PumpkinMuffins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/snacks/2024/08/28/snacks-PumpkinMuffins.html</guid>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>quick &amp; easy</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>snacks</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cranberry Chutney</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine sugar and water in a saucepan over medium heat, bring to a boil. (BOILING SUGAR IS EXTREMELY HOT, BE CAREFUL)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice, seed and blend your whole orange (peel too, the bitterness is important)!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel and slice ginger into VERY thin slices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add blended orange and ginger slices to sugar water, reduce heat and simmer, uncovered for 20 min.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add cranberries, cinnamon, and cloves to pot, cook another 20 minutes until thickened - you’re shooting for jam consistency, this should not at all be juicy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put in refridgerator to cool, can be made up to a week in advance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2024/08/28/sides-CranberryChutney.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2024/08/28/sides-CranberryChutney.html</guid>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>make-ahead</category>
        
        <category>one-pot</category>
        
        <category>fruit</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Refried Beans</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add dry beans to a bowl and fill with water, water should be about an inch about the level of the beans. Cover and set aside overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drain beans, add to crock pot. Fill bowl with water and add to crock pot, you should have enough water to fully cover the beans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add salt and garlic to crockpot, stir a few times with a spoon. Set on HIGH. Leave for 6 hrs, stirring once or twice while cooking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove beans from water, but DO NOT TOSS THE WATER. Add about a half cup of the reserve water, blen using an immersion blender. Add more water as needed to get desired consistency (it will tighten up a bit when you add to the bacon).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice bacon to smalls pieces. Cook in large skillet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once bacon is cooked, add blended beans to skillet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add garlic salt and stir a few times using a spatula.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce heat immediately, ensuring the bacon grease is fully mixed into the beans. Sprinkle cheese on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow cheese to melt, serve in skillet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2024/08/23/sides-RefriedBeans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2024/08/23/sides-RefriedBeans.html</guid>
        
        <category>bacon</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mexican Rice</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add olive oil to medium saucepan, heat on medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add rice to oil and toast until lightly browned. You’ll need to let is rest a little longer than you’d expect, but don’t forget it because it goes from perfectly browned to thoroughly burnt in the blink of an eye!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While your rice is toasting, Add tomatoes (cut in half), onion (cut in fourths), 1 cup chicken broth, garlic and salt to blender. Blend thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added blender contents to rice, add rest of chicken broth and reduce heat to low. Cover rice and cook for 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once cooked, fluff rice and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2024/08/23/sides-MexicanRice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2024/08/23/sides-MexicanRice.html</guid>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>rice</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Potato Skin Casserole</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 500 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice potatoes into 1/2-inch cubes, leaving the skin on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, whisk together olive oil, vinegar, garlic, salt, pepper and paprika.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reserve 1/2-3/4 cup of sauce, to coat chicken. (You can always some back to your potatoes if necessary).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add potatoes to sauce, tossing to coat thoroughly. Pour potatoes into a deep casserole dish. **A deep dish makes it MUCH easier to toss your potatoes when you roast them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roast potatoes for 45 minutes, tossing every 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While your potatoes are roasting, fry up your bacon. **A general rule of mine is to add a few extra pieces, just in case you get sniped-by yourself or others tempted by the bacon smell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rough-chop your bacon once cooled, and mix in a small bowl with the cheddar cheese and chopped green onions. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice your chicken into bite-sized pieces (about 1-inch cubes), and add to your previously used potato bowl. Add your reserved sauce to the raw chicken and toss to coat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’ve finished your 45 minute potato roast, toss the potatoes one last time. Add the chicken evenly to the top of the potatoes, and then coat with your cheese and bacon mixture. Reduce oven temperature to 400 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook for about 20 minutes, until the cheese bubbles. Allow to cool before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/casseroles/2024/08/23/casseroles-PotatoSkinCasserole.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/casseroles/2024/08/23/casseroles-PotatoSkinCasserole.html</guid>
        
        <category>potatoes</category>
        
        <category>bacon</category>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        
        <category>casseroles</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Garlic Bok Choy</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim ends from bok choy, about 1-2 inches from bottom of bulb. Quarter if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add oil to medium pot, heat over medium-high heat - the oil will appear to shimmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add garlic, ginger and salt to oil, reduce eat to medium, and mix together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immediately add bok choy, mixing to coat with oil mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover and allow to cook down about 3-4 minutes. The bok choy will noticeably cook down and because a vivid green.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add water and sugar, mixing thoroughly. Cover and cook 2 additional minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from heat and serve immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2022/02/26/GarlicBokChoy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2022/02/26/GarlicBokChoy.html</guid>
        
        <category>veggies</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peanut Butter Blossoms</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat over to 350 degrees F, setting rack in center position.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unwrap Hershy’s Kisses, set aside in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a separate bowl, combine flour, baking soda, and salt. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In stand mixer with the paddle attachment, cream together butter and peanut butter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add sugars and continue until fully mixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add milk and vanilla extract until fully mixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting mixer to low, add 1/2 of the flour mixture until fully combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add egg to batter, continuing to mix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the last of the flour mixture, mixing until fully blended. If the dough is too dry (flaky like pie crust rather than a cohesive batter), add milk 1 tbsp at a time until the batter comes together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place 1 cup of granulated sugar in a bowl or small plate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinch off walnut-sized pieces of dough (approximately 1-1.5 oz), roll into a ball, and then roll in the granulated sugar. Place on cookie sheet lined with parchment paper. Be sure not to place cookies too close togther as they spread significantly during baking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake cookies for 11 to 13 minutes. The cookies will only lighten a bit and will be soft to the touch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immediately place one Hershey’s kiss in the center of each cookie, pushing down slightly to create a small cradle for the kiss in the dough. DO NOT touch again until fully cooled.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immediately transfer cookies to cooling rack via spatula.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/desserts/2022/02/18/desserts-PeanutButterBlossoms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/desserts/2022/02/18/desserts-PeanutButterBlossoms.html</guid>
        
        <category>cookies</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parmesan Roasted Asparagus</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set your oven broil - HIGH. Cover a cookie sheet with aluminum foil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread asparagus over cookie sheet, add salt &amp;amp; pepper to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle parmesan cheese over asparagus evenly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roast asparagus on top rack for 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool 5 minutes, then serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2022/02/17/sides-ParmesanRoastedAsparagus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2022/02/17/sides-ParmesanRoastedAsparagus.html</guid>
        
        <category>veggies</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Country Green Beans</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook bacon in medium-large pot until fully crisp. Remove bacon and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add remaing ingredients to pot with bacon grease, cover and bring to boil on high heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce heat to medium-low, leave covered and cook about 45 minutes or until green beans are preferred texture (if you’re using fresh green beans, you will need to cook up to an additional 30 minutes).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss bacon in green beans, leaving a few aside to garnish. Serve immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2022/02/13/sides-CountryGreenBeans.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/sides/2022/02/13/sides-CountryGreenBeans.html</guid>
        
        <category>veggies</category>
        
        <category>bacon</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chewy Oatmeal Cookies</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350 degrees F and line 2-3 baking sheets with parchment paper or silicone mats.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together flour, cinnamon, baking soda, and salt in the bowl of a stand mixer with a paddle attachment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 1 egg at a time, then vanilla. Mix thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add oats and raisins, mixing thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinch off walnut-sized pieces (about 2 oz.), roll into balls and place on cookie sheet, spacing about 2 inches apart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake 13 minutes, until edges are golden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer immediately to cooling rack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://effintasty.com/recipes/desserts/2022/02/09/desserts-OatmealCookies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://effintasty.com/recipes/desserts/2022/02/09/desserts-OatmealCookies.html</guid>
        
        <category>cookies</category>
        
        <category>vegetarian</category>
        
        
        <category>desserts</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
