<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Effin&#39; Tasty</title>
    <description>Effin&#39; Tasty is a cooking site dedicated to food, and the tastiest ways to  prepare it. We have recipes and prep techniques, along with delicous pictures.
</description>
    <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 21:28:48 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 21:28:48 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Falafel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: This is a great recipe for meal prep, to eat on salads or in sandwiches for the work week. Traditionally, falafel is fried, but I prefer to bake it to keep things a bit lighter. I usually eat as a salad with only this and feta cheese. **This recipe is marked gluten-free, but please be sure to check your ingredients (especially your soy sauce) that they are marked “gluten-free” before you serve to anybody with dietary restrictions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 375 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add onion and garlic to food processor and blend thoroughly. Scrape into separate bowl and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chickpeas, salt, cumin, parsley and cilantro to food processor and blend until thoroughly blended-but NOT a paste!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add onion and garlic paste to chickpea mixture, blending thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add baking powder and 1 tablespoon flour to the chickpea and onion mixture, pulsing in the food processor until a dough starts to form. You’re looking for a playdough-like consistency. Continue to add flour until you get the desired consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrape dough into separate bowl, ensuring that all ingredients are thoroughly mixed from the corners of the food processing bowl. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spray cookie sheet with cooking spray. **If you’re going to fry your falafel, heat your oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a medium cookie scoop or spoon, place walnut-sized balls of dough onto the cookie sheet. Flatten each ball with a spoon or fork. **The falafel will barely expand when baking, so these disks can be pretty close to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 40 minutes, allow to cool before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/sides/2016/10/16/sides-falafel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/sides/2016/10/16/sides-falafel.html</guid>
        
        <category>quick&amp;easy</category>
        
        <category>vegan</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        <category>healthy/light</category>
        
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>sides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Turkey Chilli</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: This is my go-to lunchtime meal during the week, and super delicious. I usually eat one serving with 1/2 cup of white rice, and 1/2 cup of black beans. If you individually store your leftover servings, it’s easier to reheat for each lunch! **This recipe is marked gluten-free, but please be sure to check your ingredients (especially your soy sauce) that they are marked “gluten-free” before you serve to anybody with dietary restrictions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook ground turkey thoroughly in a large wok.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add diced tomatoes, cumin, garlic, salt, onion, pepper, red pepper and chipotle to wok, mixing thoroughly. Reduce heat and simmer for 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice and black beans, or eat ungarnished!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/10/16/maindishes-TurkeyChilli.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/10/16/maindishes-TurkeyChilli.html</guid>
        
        <category>quick&amp;easy</category>
        
        <category>one-pot</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        <category>healthy/light</category>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lemon Garlic Chicken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: This recipe is very garlicked up-we’re a garlic household. The fresh garlic keeps the sharpness, the granulated intensifies the garlic flavor, and the salt brings a bit more depth. You can use this on chicken or a white fish (like tilapia), but it works better with chicken. This is a marinade, so the flavor if tested should be VERY strong-if you taste test, you’re really just looking for balance, as your chicken will obviously not be as strongly flavored. **This recipe is marked gluten-free, but please be sure to check your ingredients (especially your soy sauce) that they are marked “gluten-free” before you serve to anybody with dietary restrictions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
This is a tasty recipe that I’ve worked on for quite a while. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim and prepare your chicken breasts, cutting at least 3 slits into each piece.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add your olive oil, lemon juice, minced garlic, granulated garlic, garlic salt, and pepper to a marinading container (such as a tupperware), whisk all together until thoroughly blended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spoon the blended marinade into the slits of the chicken breasts, and submerge into the marinade-be sure that the chicken is covered by more than just olive oil. Let rest in the refrigerater overnight if possible, but at minimum 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from the fridge, and grill your chicken (BBQ is best, but the chicken can be baked as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/10/16/maindishes-LemonGarlicChicken.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/10/16/maindishes-LemonGarlicChicken.html</guid>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>grill</category>
        
        <category>quick&amp;easy</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        <category>make-ahead</category>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lemon Butter Chicken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: Be careful when adding your chicken to your pan that the butter doesn’t splatter-it burns! I usually serve this with pasta and a starchy vegetable, like brussels sprouts.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare and trim your chicken breasts, cutting to cutlet-sized pieces (a little bit larger than tenders).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat your pan to medium-high, melting half of your butter (4 tablespoons) and allowing it to brown a bit. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While your pan heats, cover each cutlet with one coat of flour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After your butter has browned a bit, add half of your lemon juice. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place your chicken in the pan, allowing it to cook in the lemon butter for 10 minutes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take chicken out of pan, add the other half of the butter and lemon juice to the pan, allowing the butter to melt. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once melted, add the chicken back to the pan, uncooked-side down. Allow to cook for an additional 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once fully cooked, add chicken to serving dish, scraping the juices from the pan into the dish.    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/10/16/maindishes-LemonButterChicken.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/10/16/maindishes-LemonButterChicken.html</guid>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>quick&amp;easy</category>
        
        <category>basics</category>
        
        <category>one-pot</category>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Loaded Baked Potato Casserole</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: This recipe is as delicious as it is time-intensive. The prep time can overlap some of the prep time, so it’s not fully 2 hours that you’ll need to make this, but it’s not a quick week night meal. If you need to reduce the spice, increase your olive oil to hot sauce proportion (you really need to have enough wet ingredients, so don’t just cut hot sauce). Serve it up with ranch dressing or sour cream, and you’re all set! this casserole delivers truly magical leftovers too! **This recipe is marked gluten-free, but please be sure to check your ingredients (especially your soy sauce) that they are marked “gluten-free” before you serve to anybody with dietary restrictions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 500 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice potatoes into 1/2-inch cubes, leaving the skin on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, whisk together olive oil, hot sauce, salt, pepper and paprika. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reserve 1/2-3/4 cup of sauce, to coat chicken. (You can always some back to your potatoes if necessary).  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add potatoes to sauce, tossing to coat thoroughly. Pour potatoes into a deep casserole dish. **A deep dish makes it MUCH easier to toss your potatoes when you roast them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roast potatoes for 45 minutes, tossing every 15 minutes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While your potatoes are roasting, fry up your bacon. **A general rule of mine is to add a few extra pieces, just in case you get sniped-by yourself or others tempted by the bacon smell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rough-chop your bacon once cooled, and mix in a small bowl with the cheddar cheese and chopped green onions. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice your chicken into bite-sized pieces, and add to your previously used potato bowl. Add your reserved sauce to the raw chicken and toss to coat. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’ve finished your 45 minute potato roast, toss the potatoes one last time. Add the chicken evenly to the top of the potatoes, and then coat with your cheese and bacon mixture. Reduce oven temperature to 400 degress F. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook for about 20 minutes, until the cheese bubbles. Allow to cool before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/casseroles/2016/08/13/casseroles-LoadedBakedPotatoCasserole.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/casseroles/2016/08/13/casseroles-LoadedBakedPotatoCasserole.html</guid>
        
        <category>potatoes</category>
        
        <category>bacon</category>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        
        <category>casseroles</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Country Baked Chicken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: I admit that I am not a huge fan of mayonnaise, and I use it as sparingly as possible-but the mayo coat makes this chicken SO JUICY. As with all tenders, the key is get equal-sized tenders, to ensure they cook evenly. If your tenders aren’t equal size/thickness, you will likely have both undercooked and overcooked/dry tenders-seriously detracting from your delicious meal. The spice is great, and it’s a pretty easy tender to assemble. Give it a try, you won’t regret it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place a wire cooking rack on a cookie sheet (the cookie sheet will catch any panko that falls from your nuggets). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trim and cut your chicken into tender-sized pieces. Whatever size you consider this to be, the key is to have equal pieces-this ensures they will cook evenly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large freezer bag, assemble the wet coat: add mayo, ground black pepper, granulated garlic, and 1 tablespoon of paprika. Mix thouroughly, ensuring there are no pockets of spice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chicken nuggets to the freezer bag, tossing to coat.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, combine the panko with the remaining paprika and garlic salt, ensuring the paprika and garlic are evenly distributed within the panko.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coat each nugget with the panko mixture, placing each breaded nugget on the wire cooking rack. **I typically dedicate one hand to the wet mixture and one hand to the dry, to keep your breading as clean as possible. Use one hand to pull the nugget from the bag, placing on top of the breading. Use your other hand to toss the breading over the nugget.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place cookie sheet and wire rack in oven, cooking for 25 minutes (longer if you have larger nuggets)s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/08/12/maindishes-CountryBakedChicken.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/08/12/maindishes-CountryBakedChicken.html</guid>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>quick&amp;easy</category>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>White Gravy Chicken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: This has been one of my favorite weeknight meals since high school, when my aunt introduced me to this ridiculously easy (and delicious!) meal. It is best served with plain white rice and steamed broccoli. **This recipe is marked gluten-free, but please be sure to check your ingredients (especially your soy sauce) that they are marked “gluten-free” before you serve to anybody with dietary restrictions. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare your chicken cutlets by cutting off any excess fat or skin. Cut each prepared breast to half thickness (your knife should be moving parallel to your cutting surface). You should have 6 chicken cutlets, but you can cut to smaller pieces if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place chicken cutlets in a casserole dish, being careful to have no overlapping chicken. Equal depth of the chicken is key, to ensure that everything is consistently cooked through. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, combine sour cream and cream of mushroom soup to make the gravy (for those less inclined towards sour cream, you can easily cut the sour cream in half or add an extra can of cream of mushroom, if you want a lot of gravy [I always do]). Combine thoroughly using a whisk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrape the white gravy on top of the chicken, making sure the chicken is fully and evenly covered. **If this does not need to be gluten-free, sprinkle the top of the dish with breadcrumbs, for a crunchy texture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake at 350 degrees F for 30 minutes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/07/17/maindishes-WhiteGravyChicken.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/mains/2016/07/17/maindishes-WhiteGravyChicken.html</guid>
        
        <category>quick&amp;easy</category>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        
        <category>mains</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BLT Stuffed Tomatoes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;READ THIS FIRST: These are incredibly addictive-I have made as many as 180 for a 25 person party, and I’ve NEVER had any leftover. You should plan for at least 5 tomatoes per person. You will likely have an excess of aioli, as this should be enough for as many as 75 tomatoes-just serve it on the side as a dip! I would also recommend making the aioli a day ahead to save time when you need to serve. Do NOT use olive oil for your aioli (which I know makes it not really an aioli)! **This recipe is marked gluten-free, but please be sure to check your ingredients (especially your soy sauce) that they are marked “gluten-free” before you serve to anybody with dietary restrictions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aioli First (you can make this a day ahead):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the chipotle, soy sauce, sugar, and liquid smoke in a blender. **Even though this is an exceedingly small volume for a full-sized blender, it will work! An immersion blender or a food processor will not work because the blade is not low enough in the bowl (I’ve tried-and failed). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium bowl, whisk together the egg yolk, lemon juice and Dijon mustard until fully incorporated. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisking constantly, start to slowly add the grapeseed oil-you want a very small, stead stream. **If you see that the oil is separated from the egg yolk mixture, stop pouring and whisk until all ingredients are incorporated, then resume your oil pouring. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add your blender contents to your oil mixture-be sure to scrape your blender blade with a spatula to get everything you can back out of your blender, because your blender has all of the flavor! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the Tomatoes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hull your tomatoes by cutting off the bottom and top of the tomatoes. You want to cut the bottom off so that the tomatoe can stand up on its own, and you need to cut off the top so that you can get your tomato huller in (if you don’t have a huller, we’ve hulled with a combination of chopsticks, rolling and a small paring knife, but get the huller-it will change your life). **This is an exceedingly tedious task, and as such I usually delegate to my dear boyfriend Tyler. Immediately place hulled tomatoes in the fridge. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice your bacon width-wise, getting about 10-12 pieces of bacon per slice. Be sure to have at least enough bacon pieces as you have tomatoes, with a few left over-just in case (Tyler always snipes a piece of bacon). Fry these until crispy, and cover with a towel until you’re ready to stuff your tomatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice your lettuce leaves into small pieces along the crispy vein of the leaf. This will make it easier to stuff the tomato if you have the firm lettuce vein to push into the tomato-and it adds a fresh crunch to compliment the bacon when eaten.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipe your aioli into each tomato, filling about 1/3 of the inside of the tomato. **To prepare for piping, but you aioli in a freezer bag (a sandwich bag is a little too thin), and cut a very small corner off of the bag-the whole created should be about half the size of a #2 pencil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After piping is complete, put any leftover aioli back into the fridge to be served with the tomatoes as a dip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a piece of bacon and a piece of tomato together, and place into the tomato. **This part is also tedious, but as you go you’ll hit your groove and pick up the pace. Especially if you do over 100.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/appetizers/2016/07/16/appetizers-BLTtomatoes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://127.0.0.1:4000//recipes/appetizers/2016/07/16/appetizers-BLTtomatoes.html</guid>
        
        <category>bacon</category>
        
        <category>gluten-free</category>
        
        <category>no-cook</category>
        
        
        <category>appetizers</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
